Gregory Foster

Craftsman of Computation and Information

Address:

Austin, Texas, USA

Phone:

+1 512.627.4734

Email:

greg@foojutsu.com (mailto:greg@foojutsu.com)

Website:

https://keybase.io/gregoryfoster (https://keybase.io/gregoryfoster)

gregoryfoster @ twitter (https://twitter.com/gregoryfoster)

gregoryfoster @ github (https://github.com/gregoryfoster)

gregoryfoster @ linkedin (https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregoryfoster/)

About

I am a full-stack web developer with a preference for interpreted languages (Python, Ruby, JavaScript). My strengths are on the server side and in the cloud. My experience extends above programming to product management, where I learned strategic trade-offs that guide feature selection and prioritization. My experience extends below programming to systems and operations, granting me an appreciation for the often thankless work required to ensure iron runs hot 24/7/365. I have years of remote collaboration experience and welcome clients with hard problems to solve.

Skills

Programming

- Python, novice, +1 year
- Cypher, novice, +1 year
- Ruby, intermediate, +10 years
- PHP, intermediate, +10 years
- Javascript, intermediate, +15 years
- CSS/HTML/HTML5, expert, +15 years
- SQL, expert, +15 years
- Bash, intermediate, +10 years,
- Java, no longer used
- Perl, no longer used

Technology

- Git, Subversion
- GitHub, JIRA
- Docker
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- Neo4j
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Apache, nginx, Caddy
- Solr
- WordPress
- Web Scraping
- APIs
- Ruby on Rails
- Django
- ¡Query

Languages

- English
- · Spanish, basic

Work Experience

foojutsu

Founder

Jan 2017 - Present

http://foojutsu.com (http://foojutsu.com)

Software and Data Consultancy

 foojutsu wrangles code and data. We provide data insight services for groups who sense opportunities to extract actionable meaning and value from data. We can help with data source identification, retrieval, and management including third-party public information requests.

Consumer Reports

Technology Manager, Austin

Aug 2014 - Jun 2016

http://www.consumerreports.org/ (http://www.consumerreports.org/)

Managed the Consumer Reports Information Technology teams in Austin

- Represented teams upstream, communicated information downstream
- * Simultaneously wore Product Managment and Web Development hats

Consumers Union

Product Manager, stori.es

Jan 2011 - Jun 2016

https://www.stori.es/ (https://www.stori.es/)

Software-as-a-Service for non-profits to gather, curate, and deploy user-generated data and story content

- Persistently championed an unprecedented intrapreneurial startup within a venerable organization. Sought out and procured more than \$1M in internal and grant-based funding throughout the on-going lifecycle of the product.
- · Led product vision and user-experience design processes.
- Hired and remotely collaborated with distributed engineering and operations firm to communicate design specifications, approve stack choices, test, and deploy features into production environment.
- Monitored mission-critical infrastructure for multiple clients for years, necessarily encountering and managing several emergency situations.
- Open sourced entire product, a first at this organization, requiring recruitment of Legal and IT staff.
- Product utilized by Advocacy and Public Policy staff, journalists, and public officials to humanize complicated policy work and articles with the stories of real people.

Consumers Union

Web Developer

May 2007 - Dec 2011

https://consumersunion.org (https://consumersunion.org)

Web and data generalist for Advocacy and Public Policy division of large non-profit

- Migrated legacy web infrastructures and content to self-hosted WordPress; trained nontechnical staff on content creation. Operated and administered WordPress sites.
- Programmed multiple WordPress themes for policy-specific microsites and flagship website.
- Created Rails-based web application for importing, organizing, and searching content collected through Convio web forms. The success of this prototype led to the creation of the stori.es product.
- Supported division's email marketing efforts.
- Programmed custom scripts for tactical data projects.

Coastal Preservation and Development Foundation

Volunteer and Technical Advisor

Jun 2006 - Aug 2006

Climate change data collection and analysis in Thailand

- Updated the NGO's Microsoft Excel data collection spreadsheets to integrate with a Microsoft Access database architecture via a Visual Basic ADODB data layer.
- Trained to scuba dive and swam the reefs to observe and count lifeforms.

Hoover's, Inc.

Java Software Engineer

Jan 2003 - Feb 2005

http://www.hoovers.com/ (http://www.hoovers.com/)

Small team ported, maintained, and enhanced data entry application

- Migrated TCL codebase to J2EE
- · Started as a contractor and was invited to join the company
- Led a sucessful redesign and refactoring project

Latin American Information Network Center (LANIC) @ the University of Texas

Systems Analyst

Jun 2002 - Nov 2002

http://lanic.utexas.edu/ (http://lanic.utexas.edu/)

Six-month contract with university department

- Migrated Latin American Research Review (LARR) journal database and website to LANIC server
- * Redesigned Latin American Periodical Table of Contents (LAPTOC) database
- * Setup new Sun IT infrastructure

The Cobalt Group

Java Software Engineer

Dec 2000 - May 2002

http://www.cdkglobal.com/ (http://www.cdkglobal.com/)

J2EE software development for the automotive industry

- JSP/servlets using Jakarta Struts
- · JDBC
- TogetherJ
- BEA WebLogic Server

IBM

Internet Application Developer and Team Lead

Feb 1999 - May 2000

https://www.ibm.com/ (https://www.ibm.com/)

Perl development on IBM's global order processing extranet

- Managed team of five developers through four production releases
- Handled emergency situations
- Application processed \$2.45B orders in 1999

Education

Texas A&M University (College Station, Texas, USA)

1993 - 1998

Computer Science

Interests

- Computer Science
- Open Data, Open Government, and Public Information
- Environmental Issues and Climate Change
- * Reuse, Recycling, and Circular Economics
- Music, Art, Film, Writing

Generated using © 2017 Gregory Foster I Download PDF (gregory_foster-resume.pdf) I Print I Top hanula/resume (https://github.com/hanula/resume)